dsm.com 2017-12-23

# Privacy Policy | DSM

### General

This Privacy & Cookie Statement applies to all personal information collected and used by the DSM entity responsible for the relevant part of the website.  The Privacy & Cookie Statement is based on the DSM Privacy Code for Customer, Supplier and Business Partner Data. The code and the particulars of the responsible DSM entity can be found under the button "Legal Information" on the left navigation menu of the page. The DSM entity which is responsible for the relevant part of the website is hereinafter referred to as “DSM”.

DSM respects your privacy and complies with the provisions of the Dutch Act on the Processing of Personal Data and the EU-privacy legislation.

### Cookies

We shall only store so called “cookies” on your computer when you have provided us with your consent by clicking on the appropriate button(s) during your visit of our website. Cookies are small text files that your browser stores locally on your computer. Cookies allow us to recognize your computer the next time you visit us. By doing so, DSM is able to improve user-friendliness of the website and to adjust the website to your needs. Most Internet browsers are set to accept these cookies automatically.

The type of personal information we collect as a result of a cookie is specific to your computer and may include the Internet Protocol (IP) address, the date and time you access our website and what parts of the website are visited. We collect the foregoing personal information to monitor the usage and usefulness of our website, for statistical purposes and to send you information about our company and our (new) products and services, which suit your interest.

You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to refuse receiving it. You can also withdraw your consent at all times by re-entering our website and select the right options. By changing settings, you can also determine that your browser will not accept cookies from this website. Be aware that in such events you may no longer be able to use all the possibilities and features of our website.

### Google Analytics

Currently we are using Google Analytics to analyze the audience of the website and improve our content. No personal information is collected from Google Analytics. For further information on the privacy policy concerning Google Analytics, please go here: [www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

### Collection of data, purpose and recipients

We collect personal data when you provide it to us (e.g. name, address, postal code, city, phone number and e-mail address), through registration, completion of forms or e-mails, as part of an order for products or services, inquiries or requests or other situations in which you have chosen to provide personal information to us.

Your data shall be processed for the purposes of realization of any agreement, between you and DSM, fulfilling a request from you for information or advice, meeting statutory or other legal requirements, providing an optimal service and sending you information about our company and our (new) products or services, which suit your interest.

We may provide your data to our DSM group companies for the same purposes as referred to above. Our group companies will also process your data in accordance with the DSM Privacy Code for Customer, Supplier and Business Partner Data and this Privacy & Cookie statement .

Your personal data will only be provided to (or used on behalf of) third parties for direct marketing purposes after you have been offered the opportunity to object thereto. These third parties will not use your personal information for any other purposes than what we have agreed with them, within the scope of the DSM Privacy Code for Customer, Supplier and Business Partner Data. DSM requests those third parties to implement adequate levels of protection in order to safeguard your personal information.  Your personal data will not be transferred to parties located in countries outside the European Economic Area,  which do not have an adequate level of protection  according to the DSM Privacy Code for Customer, Supplier and Business Partner Data.

All DSM group companies and third parties will process your personal data according to instructions of DSM.

### Children

The DSM websites are not intended to be used by persons under the age of sixteen (16) and we will not knowingly allow such visitors to use DSM’s websites.

### Linked sites

Please be aware that the DSM Privacy & Cookie Statement does not apply to other non-DSM websites, also:

  * if you access these other sites using a link on our website; or
  * if you link to our site from another website.

### Right to access / rectification / object

At all times you can request access to and/or rectification and/or deletion of your data if such data are incorrect or irrelevant for the mentioned purposes. For these purposes please send us your request for access, correction or removal of your personal data via [email](mailto:webmaster.internet@dsm.com).

At all times you can object against the use of your data for direct marketing purposes.

### Retention period

DSM will not retain the personal data that are obtained through this website for longer than necessary, unless the data has to be kept for a longer period according to the DSM Privacy Code for Customer, Supplier and Business Partner Data.

### Security of your data

The storage and transfer of your data through the internet are secured by means of the current usual techniques.

Version February 5, 2015 PS
